Defy the odds.
Young Woman and the Sea is a history, drama film directed by Joachim Rønning.
This is the extraordinary true story of Trudy Ederle, the first
woman to successfully swim the English Channel.
Through the steadfast support of her older sister and supportive trainers, she overcame adversity and the animosity of a patriarchal
society to rise through the ranks of the Olympic swimming team and complete the 21-mile trek from France to England.
Trudy Ederle, played by Daisy Ridley.
Meg Ederle, played by Tilda Cobham-Hervey.
Bill Burgess, played by Stephen Graham.
Henry Ederle, played by Kim Bodnia.
Gertrude Ederle, played by Jeanette Hain.
James Sullivan, played by Glenn Fleshler.
Young Woman and the Sea is a 2024 American biographical sports film directed by Joachim
Rønning and written by Jeff Nathanson, based on the 2009 book by Glenn Stout.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Jerry Bruckheimer Films, the film stars Daisy Ridley as Gertrude Ederle,
an American competitive swimmer who became the first woman to swim across the English Channel.
It also stars Tilda Cobham-Hervey, Stephen Graham, Kim Bodnia,
Christopher Eccleston, and Glenn Fleshler in supporting roles.
Development on the film began in 2015 after producer Jerry Bruckheimer acquired the film rights to the book, and established a
distribution deal with Paramount Pictures, with Nathanson attached to write it and Lily James cast as Ederle.
Paramount eventually put the project in turnaround.
In 2020, Walt Disney Pictures acquired the project with Ridley
set to portray Ederle and Rønning to direct it.
Principal photography took place between May and June 2022.
Young Woman and the Sea premiered at the Hollywood
Roosevelt Hotel in Los Angeles on May 16, 2024.
Originally set for release by Disney on its streaming service Disney+, the film had a limited
theatrical release after positive test screenings in the United States on May 31, 2024.
It received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of english channel, biography,
based on true story, swimming, 1920s.
The tone is emotional.